<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://deut-erium.github.io/ramblings/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://deut-erium.github.io/ramblings/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2022-06-01T05:24:41+05:30</updated><id>https://deut-erium.github.io/ramblings/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Ramblings</title><subtitle>Ridiculously random ramblings residing in my mind
</subtitle><author><name>deuterium</name><email>farziemailid69@gmail.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">Pondering randoblurry improvements</title><link href="https://deut-erium.github.io/ramblings/2022/02/04/randoblurry-update.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pondering randoblurry improvements" /><published>2022-02-04T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2022-02-04T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>https://deut-erium.github.io/ramblings/2022/02/04/randoblurry-update</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://deut-erium.github.io/ramblings/2022/02/04/randoblurry-update.html"><![CDATA[<p>Perhaps a list of random words is not so fulfilling given it could be just 4 nouns which would be very difficult to put together in a sentence which would end up making no 
sense at all. What I learned from my discussion with Z is that I need a proportionate mix of parts of speech.<br />
Moreover I can have additional difficulty by using the words in order they were presented!</p>]]></content><author><name>deuterium</name><email>farziemailid69@gmail.com</email></author><category term="wordgame" /><category term="randoblurry" /><category term="ponder" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Perhaps a list of random words is not so fulfilling given it could be just 4 nouns which would be very difficult to put together in a sentence which would end up making no sense at all. What I learned from my discussion with Z is that I need a proportionate mix of parts of speech. Moreover I can have additional difficulty by using the words in order they were presented!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Trying out randoblurry</title><link href="https://deut-erium.github.io/ramblings/2022/02/03/randoblurry-test.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Trying out randoblurry" /><published>2022-02-03T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2022-02-03T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>https://deut-erium.github.io/ramblings/2022/02/03/randoblurry-test</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://deut-erium.github.io/ramblings/2022/02/03/randoblurry-test.html"><![CDATA[<p>Interaction with a friend about randoblurry<br />
<!--more--></p>

<h1 id="trying-out-the-idea-of-randoblurry">Trying out the idea of randoblurry</h1>

<p>Excited to play the new game I created, I asked a friend of mine if it seems reasonable. Let’s call her “Z” and me “D”.</p>

<p>Z: This doesn’t appear to be much fun.<br />
D: Try out giving me some 4 random words of your choice.<br />
Z: Alright.<br />
Z: Fetish random obligatory meaningless<br />
D: Z’s <em>obligatory</em> response to trigger word <em>fetish</em> of D might seem <em>meaningless</em> to some, but to him its his daily source of entertainment.<br />
Z: Oh it was nice!<br />
D: I know right!?<br />
Z: Wait, I’ll read your blog again.<br />
D: Sure, just imagine you will keep on giving 4 random words and I have to connect/extend the story with the context. <br />
D: I feel the words I am getting by my approach in blog are kinda non-sensical to produce something meaningful.<br />
Z: Gotcha, here you go with your words.<br />
Z: derogatory pathway software wall<br />
D: I can feel a <em>derogatory</em> wall between us, which is still blocking our <em>pathway</em> to communicate in a language of <em>poetry</em> called <em>software</em>.<br />
Z: Oooooo.. How about inclusion, rarefraction, supersonic, behavioral<br />
D: I bet you have a physics book in your hand.<br />
Z: Yeah felt like studying but now I feel overdosed on caffiene.<br />
D: Her brain is running at such <em>supersonic</em> speeds that I can observe a <em>rarefraction</em> of her thoughts, void of <em>behavorial</em> <em>inclusion</em><br />
Z: Nice!. Aggravate punish behold superior.<br />
D: “<em>Behold</em> the <em>superior</em> Z!”, to <em>punish</em> her books, she proclaimed on the last gulp of black coffee, little did she know how it will <em>agggravate</em> her perception. <br />
Z: Damn it!<br />
D: These are not random enough :P<br />
Z: Abrogated exhort flagrant cupidity<br />
D: She considered her words random enough, only to be <em>abrogated</em> by D’s linking ability which he uses as a <em>fragrant</em> cologne to <em>exhort</em> her <em>cupidity</em><br />
Z: Probity, spurious, wily, fetter<br />
Z: Oh wait, hey it was flagrant!<br />
D: Thats how you plant to <em>fetter</em> his <em>wily</em> responses? Him missing a spelling should no way be considered <em>spurious</em> as he can still justify his <em>probity</em> by his <em>flagrant</em> capability to include words on the fly<br />
Z: I am a fan already. Go with travesty, vociferous, iconoclast, largess<br />
D: A <em>travesty</em> of Sassy Tharoor, whose vocabulary is actually her <em>largess</em>, this <em>vociferous</em> lad is a born grammatical <em>iconoclast</em>.<br />
Z: Relegate, beguile, evanescent, maelstorm<br />
D: Hmmmmm<br />
D: He <em>relegates</em> her hard found words to <em>beguile</em> her into producing yet another set of <em>evanescent</em> words. Can she in any way stop this furious <em>maelstorm</em> growing hungry with each word fed?<br />
Z: Oh lord you win, enough for today!</p>]]></content><author><name>deuterium</name><email>farziemailid69@gmail.com</email></author><category term="wordgame" /><category term="randoblurry" /><category term="testing" /><category term="dialogue" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Interaction with a friend about randoblurry]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New word game - randoblurry</title><link href="https://deut-erium.github.io/ramblings/2022/02/02/randoblurry0001.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New word game - randoblurry" /><published>2022-02-02T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2022-02-02T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>https://deut-erium.github.io/ramblings/2022/02/02/randoblurry0001</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://deut-erium.github.io/ramblings/2022/02/02/randoblurry0001.html"><![CDATA[<p>How can I come up with something interesting, let alone inspiring, every day without an agenda or motivation?<br />
I thought of a game today.</p>

<h2 id="randoblurry">Randoblurry</h2>
<p>People suck miserably to draw “something” on a blank canvas. Apparently its not the canvas but them :flushed:<br />
Wish I possesed the child like ability to throw my brains away to a canvas without caring about how well it actually looks!<br />
Talking about kids drawing, that reminds me of color books! Which are easier on the brains since it overcomes the hurdle of 
drawing something. Once you have something to work with, you just grate your crayons on it till your stupid little brain is happy.</p>

<p>How about a analogous stupid little template for writing something probably inconsequential but fun?</p>

<ul>
  <li>Using some sort of wordlist to generate new words</li>
  <li>Seeding the random number generator for today’s date (whichever satisfies your format-hunger, just consistent enough to be shared and enjoyed with friends)</li>
  <li>Setting up a style (need to come up with multiple formats later)</li>
  <li>Setting up a difficulty for a style (say generating 4 words at random to write a sentence comprising those words)</li>
  <li>Profit</li>
</ul>

<p>Well who cares if it makes any sense or not, alteast I had fun. Hoping someone else might too!<br />
Here’s a quick python implementation (just for the sake of lazy nerds) (skip if you dont care and only care about the outcome)</p>
<div class="language-python highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="kn">from</span> <span class="nn">nltk.corpus</span> <span class="kn">import</span> <span class="n">words</span>
<span class="kn">import</span> <span class="nn">random</span>
<span class="n">wordlist</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="n">words</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">words</span><span class="p">()</span>
<span class="n">seed</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="mi">20220202</span> <span class="c1">#cant help myself laying my hands over this beauty
</span><span class="n">difficulty</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="mi">4</span>
<span class="n">random</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">seed</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">seed</span><span class="p">)</span>
<span class="k">while</span> <span class="bp">True</span><span class="p">:</span>
  <span class="n">ego_satisfied</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nb">input</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s">"more?</span><span class="se">\n</span><span class="s">"</span><span class="p">)</span>
  <span class="k">if</span> <span class="n">ego_satisfied</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">lower</span><span class="p">()</span><span class="o">==</span><span class="s">"y"</span><span class="p">:</span>
    <span class="k">break</span>
  <span class="k">print</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">random</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">sample</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">wordlist</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="n">difficulty</span><span class="p">))</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Here we go -</p>
<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>['dandiacal', 'ciliary', 'Sacrificati', 'oysterous']
['unfittingly', 'retender', 'Kashube', 'Khorassan']
['unfainting', 'transvasation', 'legitimatist', 'Bretwaldaship']
['saltishly', 'stridence', 'hydrometric', 'progenitor']
['inestimably', 'overslur', 'benempt', 'featherwing']
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>I can’t belive that first set of words caught me offguard and I need to look up a dictionary.<br />
It seems I need to look up for a more sensible dictionary (for a n00b like me ofcourse)<br />
Or having faith on lord RNGeesus and waiting till tomorrow.<br />
Interesting to know that there exist wordgames which I can explore on dictionary sites.</p>]]></content><author><name>deuterium</name><email>farziemailid69@gmail.com</email></author><category term="wordgame" /><category term="randoblurry" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[How can I come up with something interesting, let alone inspiring, every day without an agenda or motivation? I thought of a game today. Randoblurry People suck miserably to draw “something” on a blank canvas. Apparently its not the canvas but them :flushed: Wish I possesed the child like ability to throw my brains away to a canvas without caring about how well it actually looks! Talking about kids drawing, that reminds me of color books! Which are easier on the brains since it overcomes the hurdle of drawing something. Once you have something to work with, you just grate your crayons on it till your stupid little brain is happy. How about a analogous stupid little template for writing something probably inconsequential but fun? Using some sort of wordlist to generate new words Seeding the random number generator for today’s date (whichever satisfies your format-hunger, just consistent enough to be shared and enjoyed with friends) Setting up a style (need to come up with multiple formats later) Setting up a difficulty for a style (say generating 4 words at random to write a sentence comprising those words) Profit Well who cares if it makes any sense or not, alteast I had fun. Hoping someone else might too! Here’s a quick python implementation (just for the sake of lazy nerds) (skip if you dont care and only care about the outcome) from nltk.corpus import words import random wordlist = words.words() seed = 20220202 #cant help myself laying my hands over this beauty difficulty = 4 random.seed(seed) while True: ego_satisfied = input("more?\n") if ego_satisfied.lower()=="y": break print(random.sample(wordlist,difficulty)) Here we go - ['dandiacal', 'ciliary', 'Sacrificati', 'oysterous'] ['unfittingly', 'retender', 'Kashube', 'Khorassan'] ['unfainting', 'transvasation', 'legitimatist', 'Bretwaldaship'] ['saltishly', 'stridence', 'hydrometric', 'progenitor'] ['inestimably', 'overslur', 'benempt', 'featherwing'] I can’t belive that first set of words caught me offguard and I need to look up a dictionary. It seems I need to look up for a more sensible dictionary (for a n00b like me ofcourse) Or having faith on lord RNGeesus and waiting till tomorrow. Interesting to know that there exist wordgames which I can explore on dictionary sites.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">No Year Resolution</title><link href="https://deut-erium.github.io/ramblings/2022/02/01/welcome.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="No Year Resolution" /><published>2022-02-01T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2022-02-01T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>https://deut-erium.github.io/ramblings/2022/02/01/welcome</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://deut-erium.github.io/ramblings/2022/02/01/welcome.html"><![CDATA[<p>New year resolution, except its a month too late<br />
Anti procrastination solution, something interesting to create<br />
One way internet pollution! I mindfully guard my gate<br />
Desultry involution, nor do I intend to ponder straight<br />
Grindful revolution, consistency sufficent to make great<br />
Delightful retribution, diminishing self hate<br />
Non promotry distribution, thanks for being here mate</p>]]></content><author><name>deuterium</name><email>farziemailid69@gmail.com</email></author><category term="poo-i-try" /><category term="short" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[New year resolution, except its a month too late Anti procrastination solution, something interesting to create One way internet pollution! I mindfully guard my gate Desultry involution, nor do I intend to ponder straight Grindful revolution, consistency sufficent to make great Delightful retribution, diminishing self hate Non promotry distribution, thanks for being here mate]]></summary></entry></feed>